战争要来临了
There is a war coming.
可怕的战争
A-a terrible war.
到时会一片混乱
There-there will be chaos.
街上血流成河
Rivers of blood in the streets.
我知道的
I know it!
我能预见到
I-I can see it coming.
是时候了
It's time.
总得有人接替他  那不如就让我来
Somebody has to take over; it might as well be me.
我在查这其中的联系
I'm looking for a connection
阿卡姆规划和我父母案子之间的联系
between the Arkham plan and the murders of my parents.
马罗尼只要拿到阿卡姆的一块砖
If Maroni gets even a piece of Arkham,
就证明法尔科内不中用了
it'll prove Falcone is weak.
再也别回哥谭了
Don't ever come back to Gotham.
你好啊  詹姆斯
Hello, James.
老朋友
Old friend.
我告诉过你永远别回来
I told you never to come back here!
没人会去找死人
Nobody looks for a dead man.
你想要这份工作吗
So... you want the job, or what?
是的
Yes.
我要找的不是美女
I ain't looking for no girl.
而是武器
I'm looking for a weapon.
法尔科内以为他可以在
Falcone thinks he could hit me
我的地盘上滋事  还能安然无事
in my place of business and get away with it?
我要回击
I want to hit him back.
本字幕由 YYeTs 人人影视 原创翻译
[WEB&BD版美剧字幕精编者]再加工制作
本人由衷感谢原译作者的无私奉献  并保留所有译作者的信息
如需其它剧集字幕  请登陆新浪微博（http://weibo.com/MJZM100）
或发邮件索取 lj20090303@163.com
去散步吗
Fancy a stroll?
今天天气很好
It's a lovely day.
去活动一下腿脚  呼吸点新鲜空气
Stretch the legs, breath of fresh air.
我在忙
Busy.
我想问你一个问题  布鲁斯少爷
I've got a question for you, Master Bruce.
万一所有这一切
What if all this
都只是在浪费时间呢
was a complete and utter bloody waste of time?
万一你永远找不到杀害你父母的凶手呢
What if you never discovered who killed your mom and dad?
万一你永远没机会报仇呢
What if you never get to wreak revenge?
我不想报仇
I don't want revenge.
我是想搞明白这里面的门道
I want to understand how it all works.
哥谭的运行机制
How Gotham works.
你拿个茶匙从这里
Well, you'd have more chance
挖到地球另一端的中国都更容易些
digging to China with a teaspoon.
就拿阿卡姆项目来说
Take the Arkham project for instance.
法尔科内和马罗尼的犯罪集团
How did the Falcone and Maroni
是如何在交易中拿到如此大的份额的
crime families get such big shares in the deal?
我是说
I mean,
我知道市政府腐败成性
I know City Hall is corrupt,
可韦恩集团就不能做点什么吗
but why didn't Wayne Enterprises do something?
把那个蓝色的文件夹递给我好吗
Can you pass me that blue folder over there?
好吧  作为爱好
Well, I suppose as hobbies go,
这是比把自己
this is damn sight better
当猪扒一样放在火上烤要好得多
than grilling yourself like a bloody pork chop.
不过  还是不怎么健康  你说呢
Still, not particularly healthy, is it?
谢谢
Thank you.
你有在听我说吗
Are you listening to me?
当然
Y-Yeah. Yeah, for sure.
我一会儿再去散步
I'll take a walk later.
谢谢你  阿尔弗雷德
Thank you, Alfred.
我在阿卡姆项目上分到了一杯羹
I won a piece of Arkham.
我逼市长就范
I strong-armed the mayor.
让法尔科内认输了
I made Falcone back down.
你还说我不能抢一个破赌场吗
And you're telling me that I can't rob a lousy casino?
萨尔  赌场是法尔科内的心肝宝贝
Sal, the casino is Falcone's pride and joy.
这样做意义何在
I mean, what's the point?
就为了几千块钱去招惹法尔科内吗
For a few thousand bucks, why mess with Falcone?
就是要这个效果
That's the point.
目的就是要招惹法尔科内
Messing with Falcone.
我要他和他的人都知道  我们是不会服软的
I want him and his people to know we're not backing off.
阿卡姆只是一个开始
Arkham was only the beginning.
我们要接手这里  弗兰克
We're taking over, Frankie.
一步一步来
Inch by inch.
好吧  可是
Okay, but...
没有可是
But, but, but!
去想办法
Make it happen.
是  老板
Okay, boss.
你在看什么
What are you looking at?
你有话要讲吗
You got something to say?
没有  先生
No, sir.
完全没有
Nothing at all.
何必撒谎  我要钱买毒品
收好了  伙计
Here you go, buddy.
翻译：灰灰是菇凉  爵士年代蓬蓬裙  Silence  木浅薰
翻译：Reginamoon  charcie  哥谭直属  草草
时间轴：最可爱的小胖子  Kallen  宝宝         后期：饿得慌
特效：宝宝         校对：草草        总监：草草
喂
Hey, man!
吸食
要付钱的
You got to pay for that!
别惹我  你个凡人
Do not vex me, mortal.
随你吧  宙斯
Suit yourself, Zeus.
说这话有点多余了
Hey, might look like the heel of a hobo's shoe--
这里有市中心最好的汉堡  对吗  以法连
best burgers in Midtown. Huh, Ephraim?
你说是就是吧
If you say so.
给我两个芝士汉堡
All right, I want two cheeseburgers,
不放酱汁  多加点酸黄瓜  再来两杯麦芽奶昔
uh, hold the sauce, extra pickles, two malted shakes.
我的请不要加酸黄瓜
No pickles on mine, please.
这你可得信我  吉姆
Oh, you got to trust me on this one, Jim.
是吗  好吧
Yeah? All right.
那就加上吧
Pickles, bring 'em.
你想等夏天穿泳裤时
All right, now, you want to look good
像我身材一样棒的话
in a swimsuit like me come summertime,
就得多吃这两样东西
you're gonna want a lot of this and a lot of this, huh?
真的吗
Is that right?
是你
You!
吉姆
Jim!
得了  现在是午餐时间  放松
Come on, it's lunchtime. Relax!
现在是午餐时间
It's lunchtime!
不  吉姆
No, Jim.
我们在...现在是午餐时间
We're on our... It-it's lunch!
饶了我吧大哥
Oh, brother.
吉姆  你别每次一听到警报响就炸毛
Jim, can't just pop up and jump every time you hear a bell.
哥谭市警局  有人在吗
GCPD! Anybody here?
这边  这边
Over... over here.
你没事吧  先生
You all right, sir?
没受伤吧
You okay?
谢天谢地你们来了
Thank God you're here.
有人丧命吗
Anybody dead?
应该没有
I don't think so.
那人在偷喝牛奶
Some guy, he was stealing milk.
我想制止他
I try to stop him,
他却把我的自动取款机拖走了
he hauls away my ATM machine.
好吧  既然没人死
All right, nobody dead.
而我们是凶案组的  现在又是午餐时间
We're homicide, and it's lunch.
所以只能祝您日安了  先生
So have a good day, sir.
打电话报警  自然会有人来帮你
Call 911, and someone will take good care of you.
等等  等等  只有一个人
Wait a minute, wait a minute. One guy did this?
为了几瓶牛奶就偷走你的ATM机
Stole your ATM over milk?
那人瘦瘦小小的
Little skinny-ass dude.
拿着吉他盒
Guitar case.
跟奶牛都死光了似的猛喝牛奶
Drinking milk like there's no more cows.
他说"别惹我  你个凡人"
"Don't vex me, mortal," He says.
抱歉  他说什么
Sorry, what?
听我说  如果每次有个把自己
Listen, if I had a dollar for every hobo skeez
当上帝的痞子走进门  我都能得到一美元
that walks through that door, thinks they're God,
我就不用苦逼开店了
I wouldn't be here.
但这个混蛋  他可不是闹着玩的
But this son of a bitch, he wasn't fooling around.
好吧  你能描述一下他的车
All right, you get a description of the vehicle,
车牌之类的吗
license plate, something?
他没有车
He didn't have a vehicle.
那他怎么把你的ATM从墙上拽下来的
Then how'd he pull your ATM from the wall?
他怎么拿走的
How'd he take it away?
我说的就是这个啊  伙计
That's what I'm telling you, man.
他就是赤手空拳地把机器拉走的
He pulled it out of here with his bare hands.
哥谭
第一季  第五集
《哦  我亲爱的爸爸》
--普契尼
无聊死了
I'm bored.
可怜的小宝贝啊
Poor little baby girl.
一直窝在这儿
Cooped up in here all the time.
你想要点刺激
You want some excitement.
是啊  我们能不能出去转转
Yes, I do. Can we just go somewhere and...?
这样如何
How's that?
够刺激吗
Excited now?
干吗打我
What'd you do that for?
我为什么选中了你
Why are you here with me?
因为我是你的秘密武器
I'm your secret weapon.
没错
Exactly.
但你有没有在帮我完善你自己呢
But are you helping me help you?
没有
No, you're not.
你连个曲子都学不好
You won't even learn the damn tune.
我告诉你了  这很重要
I told you this is important.
对不起  妈妈
I'm sorry, mama.
我不是你妈妈
I'm not your mama.
你虽说是我的小宝贝  但我不是你妈妈
Now, you might be my baby girl, but I'm not your mama.
你还不够格
Not yet.
这你得努力争取
You have to earn that.
这怎么可能
How is that even possible?
这家伙是谁
Who is this guy?
还没查到身份
No positive I.D.
现在只知道他是个流浪汉
As of yet, he's a street guy.
我们认为应该是这东西导致了
We think that this thing has something to do with his...
他过分亢奋
excessive joie de vivre.
我们在嫌疑人的吉他盒里找到了这个
Yeah, we found it in the suspect's guitar case.
是种药品
It's some kind of drug.
一剂药有这效果
A drug did that?
尼格玛发现了少量残留药物
Nygma found traces of the drug.
他明早就能查出这究竟是什么鬼东西
He'll have a read on what the hell this thing is by tomorrow morning.
我们会去查大力士的身份
Meantime, we'll try and ID The strong man.
我知道你们的家族都有不满
I know your families are upset.
不过让他们放心
But tell them
人人都能在阿卡姆项目中分一杯羹
everybody got a piece of the Arkham project.
这是个商业策略
It was a business decision.
我们没输  马罗尼也没赢
We didn't lose, Maroni didn't win.
但马罗尼觉得他赢了
Maroni thinks he won.
他觉得他大赢特赢了
He thinks he won a great battle.
我们得煞煞他的威风
We need to hurt him.
不行
No.
如果我们不强硬反击  他就会觉得...
If we don't push back hard, he's going to think...
尼克拉  那个蠢货只是被我牵着鼻子走罢了
Nikolai, that fool will think what I want him to think.
现在不要反击
No push back, not yet.
我们国家有一句俗话
In my country, we say,
即使是蠢货  有了牙齿  照样咬得了国王
"Even a fool may bite the king, if he has teeth."
少说点什么俗语吧  尼克
Can the folklore, Niko.
我们不在你的小破国家
We're not in your godforsaken country.
这儿是哥谭市  这里有管道设置  电力
We are here in Gotham, where we have plumbing, electricity,
还有法尔科内阁下做老大
and Don Falcone is the boss.
他对马罗尼是放长线钓大鱼  闭嘴吧你
He's playing that cluck Maroni on a long line. Done!
这么生气干吗  菲什
Why so angry, Fish?
我有话直说  这也有罪吗
I speak my mind. Is no crime.
而且我向你保证  我们国家
And I assure you, in my country,
也有全部的现代化设施
we have all modern conveniences.
唯一的区别在女人
Only difference: ladies.
她们都待在厨房  或是床上
Ladies are in kitchen or in bed,
这就因人才能而异了
depending on their talents.
你妈妈做菜肯定很差劲
I bet your mother was a lousy cook.
别谈论我妈妈
Don't speak of my mother.
不然怎样
Or what?
你要打女人吗
You gonna hit a lady?
够了
That's enough.
大家不要闹不和
There'll be no bad blood here.
对不起  法尔科内阁下
My apologies, Don Falcone.
我们需要彼此
We need each other.
我们是一家人
We're family.
打扰一下  有见过这个人吗
Excuse me. You seen this guy by chance?
没
Nah.
见过这个人吗
You seen this guy?
打扰一下
Excuse me.
见过他吗
Familiar to you, hmm?
见过这人吗
Any chance you've seen this guy?
见过  我认识他
Yeah, I know him.
他叫贝尼
That's, uh, Benny.
是个吉他手
He's a guitar player.
吸毒成瘾
Strung out like string.
他干了什么
What'd he do?
没干什么坏事
Uh, nothing bad.
其实他继承了一笔遗产
Uh, he came into an inheritance actually
-此前没人知道  -没错
- no one knew about. - That's right.
有上百万美元
Million dollars.
还有农场和马匹  真的很不错
Farm, horses, real nice.
我们在哪能找到他
You know where can we find him?
给我20块
$20.
10块
Ten.
和酒店情况一样
Same as the bodega.
这么多牛奶是怎么回事
Yeah, what's with all the dairy products?
先生
Sir?
哥谭市警局
GCPD.
把双手举起来
Let me see those hands.
帮帮我
Oh... help me.
我需要
I need...
更多的
more...
更多的什么  你服了什么
More what? What'd you take?
-告诉我  -感觉太妙了
- What is it? - It's... it felt so good.
可现在我好难受
And now I-I don't feel so good.
不太对劲
Something's wrong.
我要更多
I need more!
求你们  快去找他
Please, you have to find him.
找谁
Find who?
-那个给你药物的人吗  -没错
- The guy that gave you the stuff? - Yeah!
那人一只耳朵有伤
The man with a mangled ear.
一只耳朵有伤  我盯住他
The mangled ear. I got him.
冷静点
Stay calm.
-帮帮我  -知道了
- Help me. - We got it.
我们会帮你的  把你的...
We're gonna help. Just put your...
-不  别碰我  -先生
- No, no, no, no! - Hey, hey! Sir!
先生  冷静点
Sir, we need you to calm down.
-别紧张  -求你
- Calm down. - Please...
把双手放在身后
Put your hands behind your back!
我说了别碰我
I said no!
把东西放下
Put it down!
搞什么
What the hell?
如果这药传开  肯定不可收拾
God help us if that drug gets out.
瞧瞧这里乱成了什么样
Will you look at this shambles?
如果你妈妈还在世会怎么说
What would your mother say?
知道吗  我很想
You know, I have a half a mind to
把这些东西都扔进火里
stick all this lot straight into the bloody fire.
不要
No fire.
走着瞧
We'll see about that.
赶快起来吧
Come on, up you get.
韦恩集团明天要举办一场慈善午宴
Wayne Enterprises is hosting a charitable luncheon tomorrow.
我擅自代表你接受了他们的
And I took the liberty of accepting their kind invitation
盛情邀请  布鲁斯少爷
on your behalf, Master Bruce.
很好
Good.
有早餐吃吗
Is there breakfast?
嗯  我去给你煎个蛋吧
Yeah, I'll make you an egg.
你的意思是要去吗
Does that mean you'll go?
是的
Yes.
我有一些问题要问董事会
I have some questions I need to ask the members of the board.
什么样的问题
What kind of questions?
关于阿卡姆的问题
About Arkham.
看起来那些黑帮的股权
It seems very likely those gangsters were actually
都是韦恩集团提供的
given their shares in Arkham by Wayne Enterprises.
生意就是这么做的  不是吗
Well, that's how business is done, isn't it?
是吗
Is it?
我父母不是这么做生意的
M-My parents didn't do business that way.
对吗
Did they?
对
No.
他们不这么做  布鲁斯少爷
No, they didn't, Master Bruce.
当然  董事会也许根本就不知情
The board might not know, of course.
他们用了很多巧妙的掩盖手段
There's quite a bit of clever camouflage used.
空壳公司  海外账户等等
Shell companies, offshore accounts and so forth.
好吧  那么你
Right. So, you-you've...
就是研究这些发现的吗
learned all that from all this, did you?
调查工作做的真棒
Fantastic detective work.
但是  我还是很想把这些
I still, however, want to get the whole lot
都一把火烧了
and chuck it straight in the fire.
什么都不要烧掉  阿尔弗雷德
Don't put anything in the fire, Alfred.
这是命令
That's an order.
是  布鲁斯少爷
Right, Master Bruce.
什么都不烧
Nothing in the fire.
重大新闻
我们在哥谭市中心现场直播
We are live in downtown Gotham
一种新型致命毒品正传入大街小巷
where a deadly new drug has hit the streets.
该毒品被称为"毒蛇"  使用者
Nicknamed "Viper," users of this mystery drug
将力大无比并获得充满力量的快感
acquire great strength and a euphoric sense of power,
"毒蛇"袭击哥谭
但此状态只能持续几小时
but only for a few brief hours.
之后无一例外地都以极其悲惨的方式死去
Then, without exception, they die a horrible death.
放我出去
Let me out!
-快走  -放开我
- Come on! - Get off me!
放开我
Let go of me!
别拿你的脏手碰我
Get your crummy hands off me!
简直非凡无比
It's really quite remarkable.
毒蛇通过某种方式触发了未使用的DNA
Viper somehow activates unused DNA.
使身体开始将骨骼中的钙质当做燃料消耗
The body starts to burn calcium from the skeletal system as fuel.
导致受害者对牛奶和奶酪产生强烈渴求
Hence the victims' cravings for milk and cheese.
因为他们亟需补充被消耗的钙质
They're desperately trying to replace the missing calcium.
但是补充入不敷出
But they can't consume enough.
最终
Essentially,
他们的骨头会碎掉
their bones crumble.
于是导致他们窒息而死
Then they suffocate and die.
你以前见过这种东西吗
Have you ever seen anything like this before?
没有  谁也没见过  完全是新东西
No. Nobody has. Totally new.
我激动的心情简直无以言表
I cannot tell you how thrilled I am to be...
已经几小时没有新案件了
No new reports for a few hours now.
也许结束了  也许他们没这种药了
Maybe they're done. Maybe they ran out of the stuff.
恐怕并非如此
I doubt it.
谁会在街上散播这种东西啊
Who would put this on the street?
目的又是什么
Why?
甚至都不是在卖
Th-They're not even selling it.
完全是免费赠送的
They're giving it away.
就是这么创造市场需求
That's how you create demand.
为一种迅速致命的毒药吗
For a drug that kills you that fast?
但死前能让你觉得自己是世界之王
Well, first it makes you king of the world.
肯定会有人要的
There'll be takers.
绝对会造成伤害
There'll be mayhem, that's for sure.
但都是针对游民
But it's skell-on-skell mayhem.
如果我们让好市民都乖乖在家待几周
If we keep the decent citizens indoors for a couple of weeks,
不去管那些混蛋
let the scumbags have at it,
犯罪就终结了
voila - the end of crime.
设想真不错
Yeah, that's a nice thought.
但是不行
But no.
这东西不容易制造吧
This stuff seems hard to make, no?
这需要复杂精巧的技术
Oh, it takes a high level of technical sophistication.
是最先进的实验室造出来的
A state-of-the-art lab made this stuff.
哥谭最大最好的实验室是哪个
Okay, so who has the biggest and best lab in the city?
最好的是韦赞制药
The best is WellZyn.
但这肯定与他们无关
But this is not them.
他们是韦恩集团的子公司
They're a subsidiary of Wayne Enterprises.
身价数十亿的大企业
Multibillion-dollar corporation.
有什么理由干这种事呢
Why would they be doing this?
不知道  但不妨就从顶端开始排查吧
I don't know, but we might as well start at the top.
抓住她  抓住她
Grab her! Grab her!
-别乱动  -放开我
- Come on, here! - Let go of me!
放开我  放开我
Get off me! Get off me!
太赞了
Fascinating.
Fascinating!
爆炸性新闻  混乱持续...
Breaking news. Continued mayhem...
或许我该雇那人去拿下赌场
Maybe I should hire that guy to take the casino.
也许你该吸点"毒蛇"  鼓鼓勇气
Maybe you should snort some Viper, grow a pair.
不管怎样  我要拿下那个赌场
Either way, I want that casino taken.
没问题  我们会拿下的
Sure, we'll take it.
那里防守严密  有10个武装守卫
I mean, it's tight as a nut-- ten armed guards
防爆门  监视器
blast-proof doors, cameras.
我们会损失几个人  但我们会拿下那里的
We're gonna lose a few guys, but we'll take it.
打扰一下  先生们
Excuse me, gentlemen.
我听到了你们关于赌场的谈话
I couldn't help but overhear your conversation regarding the casino.
管好你自己的事
Go mind your business.
对不起  当然了  真对不起
I'm sorry. Of course. So sorry.
不
No.
告诉我  赌场怎么了
Tell me, what about the casino?
我认识赌场锅炉房的看门人
I know a janitor who runs the boiler room of the casino.
我相信他能轻易带你们进去
He could get you inside quite easily, I believe.
有一些没人知道的通道
There are access tunnels that nobody knows about.
通道
Access tunnels?
坐下  到这儿来
Sit down. Come here.
谢谢您  先生  这真是天大的荣幸
Thank you, sir. A great honor indeed.
你叫什么来着
What's your name again?
这儿的人都喊我"企鹅"  先生
Everyone here calls me Penguin, sir.
你不喜欢这名字  是吧
You don't like that name, huh?
好吧  你错了
Yeah, well, you're wrong.
这是个好名字
It's a good name.
很称你
Works for you.
你是怎么认识这个看门人的
So how do you know this man? The janitor?
我有些人脉
I have connections.
他可靠吗
Reliable, is he?
我觉得我可以说服他可靠点
I think I can persuade him to be.
老大  这人就是个穿西装的洗碗工
Boss, this guy is a dishwasher in a suit.
淡定
Relax.
是这样吗  企鹅
Is that right, Penguin?
你只是个洗盘子的吗
Are you just a dishwasher?
因为我觉得不像
'Cause I don't get that vibe.
你表面上毕恭毕敬  但是...
You come off as all humble, but...
你心里不安分  是吧
you got a little player in you, huh?
您真会看人啊  先生
That's very perceptive of you, sir.
我猜这就是您能被尊称为"阁下"的原因
I guess that's why you're the don.
我不是个洗盘子的
I'm not a dishwasher.
而且  可以说  我不是第一回干这个了
And this isn't my first rodeo, so to speak.
你以前干过  是吧
So, you've rode some bulls, huh?
我就知道
I knew it.
那就说来听听吧  牛仔
Well, tell all, cowboy.
我的真名叫奥斯瓦尔德・科波特
Well, my real name is Oswald Cobblepot.
我觉得等您听了我的故事
And I think that once you hear my story,
您就会认同我能成为您的得力手下  先生
you'll agree that I could be a great asset for you, sir.
是个很长很有趣的故事
It's a long, funny story really.
但以免吓着您  最重要的是...
But the headline, just so you're not surprised...
我以前为菲什・穆尼工作
I used to work for Fish Mooney.
菲什・穆尼
Fish Mooney?
是的  先生
Yes, sir.
我参与过不少法尔科内家族的生意
I was privy to many aspects of the Falcone family business.
-直到他们试图杀我  -这样啊...
- Until they tried to kill me. - Yeah, well...
没想到吧
Hello.
可以说...
Suffice it to say...
还真是个有趣的故事
That is a funny story.
我是泰勒・里斯
I'm Taylor Reece,
韦赞制药公关部的总顾问
general counsel, public relations for WellZyn.
早上好  先生们
Good morning, gentlemen.
多谢替我们省趟跑腿了
Thank you for saving us a trip.
我们一听说你们的调查就赶来了
We were en route as soon as we were apprised of your inquiries.
韦赞制药致力于营造良好的社区关系
WellZyn is committed to good community relations.
你对"毒蛇"有什么了解
What do you know about Viper?
只知道新闻上说的那些
Only what we see on the news.
韦赞制药和这起悲剧毫无关系
WellZyn has no connection to this tragedy.
我们会大力采取法律手段
We will vigorously pursue legal action
追究那些提出相反论调的人的责任
against any individuals making assertions to the contrary.
我们需要按按钮
Do you think we push a button
还是她能自动倒带
or does she just rewind automatically?
我们在找一名韦赞制药的员工
We're looking for an employee of WellZyn's.
一名耳朵严重受伤的男性
Male with a severely damaged ear.
是的
Y-Yes.
我要说明  你说的这人我的确有印象
Full disclosure-- that does raise a flag.
这是斯坦・波托斯基
That's Stan Potolsky.
他作为生化学家在我们公司做了几年
He worked for us for several years as a biochemist.
主要负责一些个人护理用品
Uh, primarily personal care products.
洗发水  牙膏之类的
Shampoos, toothpastes.
后来发生了什么事
So what happened?
斯坦觉得自己的工作不够重要而倍感受挫
Well, Stan was frustrated that he wasn't doing more important work.
他日渐不满  情绪不稳定
He grew disgruntled and unstable.
我们想给他找医生  但他拒绝了
We tried to get him help, but he resisted.
去年4月  出了件事
Last April, there was an incident.
他因为跟上司起争执
He tried to cut off his own ear
试图割掉自己的耳朵
during a disagreement with his supervisor.
看来没他想得那么容易
Guess it was harder than he thought.
我们不得不解雇他
We had to let him go.
知道他住址吗
Last known address?
他被解雇后
Well, after he was terminated,
都没回来收拾办公桌
he didn't even clear off his desk.
直接不见了  没人找得到他
Just disappeared, off the grid.
你早就知道  是不是
You knew, didn't you?
你知道是他
You knew all along it was him.
所以你急忙赶来警局
That's why you came to see us so fast.
不是这样的
That's incorrect.
只有装备先进的实验室才能制出"毒蛇"
Viper can only be produced in a state-of-the-art lab,
比如你们的实验室
like yours.
斯坦・波托斯基是个聪明人
Stan Potolsky is a brilliant man,
完全有能力建他自己的实验室
perfectly capable of building his own lab.
不过欢迎你们来检查我们的设施
But you are more than welcome to examine our facilities.
当然得有合适的许可
With full and proper clearances, of course.
当然
Of course.
我们这就去准备文件
We'll get the paperwork started.
律师
Lawyers.
都是人渣
Scumbags, the lot of them.
有一些吧
Yeah, some of them.
去找斯坦・波托斯基吧
Let's go find Stan Potolsky.
怎么  难道开车到处乱转吗
What, drive around looking for him?
不  我让调度发全境通告
No. I'll call dispatch, have them put out an APB.
好  那我去前台
All right, I'll check with the desk,
看有没有人提过他
see if his name's come up.
你是戈登吧
Gordon, right?
是的  你是谁
Yeah. Who the hell are you?
你乖乖地马上跟我走
You got to come with me now, nice and quiet like.
你说什么呢
What are you talking about?
放松  我们有个共同的朋友
Relax. We got a mutual friend.
是吗  是谁
Oh, yeah, who's that?
奥斯瓦尔德・科波特
Oswald Cobblepot.
没错  就是他
Yeah, him.
你现在要是不跟我走
And if you don't come with me now,
我们就砍下他的头
we're gonna put his head in a bag
然后寄给法尔科内
and send it to Falcone,
这样你就尴尬了  对吗
which would be embarrassing for you, no?
或许是我们被耍了
Or maybe we've been misinformed.
要是你对他毫无印象
I mean, if I'm not ringing any bells here,
你可以不用理会
you can go on your merry way.
不  我跟你走
No, I'll come.
往里挤挤
Come on, shove over.
欢迎
Welcome.
我是萨尔维多・马罗尼
I'm Salvatore Maroni.
我知道你是谁
I know who you are.
你想怎么样
What do you want?
是这样的...
Here's the thing...
吉姆  说实话就好
Jim, just tell the truth.
要喝一杯不  吉姆
You want a drink, Jim?
我在喝尼格龙尼[意大利鸡尾酒]
I'm having a Negroni.
配海鲜好极了
So good with seafood.
水
Water.
我们这位朋友讲了个精彩的故事
So, our friend here told me a fascinating story.
从没听过这么棒的故事
Never heard a story so good.
很难相信是真的
It's hard to believe it's true.
真的  是真的
It is, it's true.
闭嘴  闭嘴
Shut up! Shut up!
再说一句  我就把这个塞你喉咙里
One more word, and I'll jam this down your throat.
我也想客气点  吉姆
I try to be civil, Jim.
但我这人一句话不说两遍
But I'm not the kind of man that likes to ask twice.
所以我们这么办...
So here's how it's gonna go.
且慢  马罗尼先生  我不知道...
Slow down, Mr. Maroni. I don't know...
住口
No! No. No.
先让我说完
You let me finish.
有你说话的机会
You'll have your turn to speak.
好了
Okay, then.
我要你给我讲个故事
I want you to tell me the same exact story
要和企鹅讲的一模一样
that Penguin told me.
什么故事
What story is that?
你最好清楚  我的朋友
Oh, you better know what story, my friend.
因为如果你们俩说的故事一样
Because if you tell me the same story he told me,
我就可以相信它的真实性
then I could believe it's true.
我就会高兴
Then I'm happy.
但你们要是说的不一样  妈妈哟
But if you tell me another story, oh, mama.
就说明有人对我撒谎
Then someone's lying to me.
我不知道谁在撒谎  你们俩都别想活
And I don't know which one, and the both of youse will die.
-懂了吗  -懂了
- Understand? - Yes, I do.
很好
Good.
那么
So...
讲吧  吉姆
Tell me a story, Jim.
有人杀害了韦恩夫妇
Somebody murdered Thomas and Martha Wayne.
我和我搭档负责这个案子
My partner and I caught the case.
我们当时根本不认识...
We didn't even know each other then...
我怎么说的
What did I say?!
把他放到切片机上
Go put him on the slicer.
不要  不要
No, no, no.
如果我不满意我听到的  就把他的脸绞烂
If I don't like what I hear, slice his face prejute.
抱歉
Oh, I'm sorry.
继续
Go on.
我被卷入了一场阴谋
I was a pawn... in a conspiracy
法尔科内  市长还有哥谭市警局
between Falcone, the mayor and the GCPD
联手陷害马里奥・佩珀为韦恩案凶手
to frame Mario Pepper for the Wayne murders,
菲什・穆尼也有参与
with the help of Fish Mooney,
她是科波特先生当时的雇主
Mr. Cobblepot's employer at the time.
科波特先生把这事告诉了重案组
Mr. Cobblepot then told the whole story to the MCU.
为了证明我不会背叛他们
To prove that I wouldn't betray the conspiracy,
法尔科内命令我杀掉科波特
Falcone ordered me to kill Cobblepot.
我没下手
I didn't do it.
我放他走了
I let him live.
就是这样
And here we are.
法尔科内  穆尼  重案组警察
Falcone, Mooney, the MCU cops--
都不知道他还活着
none of them know he's alive?
他们要是知道  我早死了
If they did, I'd be dead already.
真有趣
It's delicious.
弗兰基  把企鹅带回来
Frankie! Bring the Penguin back out here.
那小杂种说的是实话
The little punk is telling the truth.
谢谢你  吉姆
Thank you, Jim.
故事很棒
Good story.
讲得也好
Told well.
大部分人在你的处境下都会吓尿了
Lot of guys in your situation, they freak out.
看看你  你个小人
There you are, you rat,
告密者  叛徒王八蛋
you snitch, you gorgeous turncoat son of a bitch.
过来  我爱你
Come here, I love you.
高兴点  弗兰基
Be happy, Frankie.
我们刚得到了对抗法尔科内的新武器
We just got a brand-new weapon against the Falcones.
简直像是圣诞节啊
It's Christmas!
节日快乐  我能走了吗
Happy holidays. Can I go now?
是的  吉姆  你可以走了
Oh, yeah, Jim, you can go.
我们说清楚
You know, just so that we, uh, understand each other,
这事要保密
you know, keep all this hush-hush.
绝不能外漏
Between us pals.
如果我需要你  会通知你的
And if I need you again, I'll call you.
谢谢
Thank you.
随你
You do that.
瞧瞧你  来吧
Look at you, come on.
去擦擦干净
Let's get you cleaned up.
瞧瞧你  来吧
Look at you. Come on.
我爱你  宝贝
I love you, baby.
-我爱你  宝贝  -好了
- I love you, baby. - Okay, now,
你的感觉还是太性感了
you're still putting too much sex on it.
纯粹点
Keep it clean.
像母亲一样
Like a mother.
我爱你  宝贝
I love you, baby.
很好
Good.
好多了
Better.
现在  你发现我撒了谎
Now, act as if you've caught me in a lie.
不要生气
Not angry.
不对
No.
失望
Disappointment.
宝贝
Oh, honey.
就是这样
There you go.
还有你的头发
Now, about your hair.
你来了
There you are.
你小子去哪了
Where the hell have you been?
有点私事
Personal business.
我们正调查案子  你突然失踪
You disappear in the middle of a case,
都不能跟我说明原因吗
you can't even tell me why?
所以才叫"私事"
That's what "personal" means.
你有麻烦了吗
You in some kind of trouble?
算了  我不想知道你的麻烦事
Look, forget it. I don't want to know your problems.
韦赞制药送来了波托斯基的私人物品
WellZyn sent by Potolsky's stuff.
自己拿一箱看吧
Grab a box.
有什么有用的吗
Anything useful yet?
没有  典型的不合群书呆子
No. Classic geeky loner.
工作就是全部生活
Lived for his work.
没有妻子
No wife,
没有家人  也没什么朋友
no family, no real friends.
是芭芭拉吗
Is it Barbara?
她有麻烦了吗
She get into something?
是的
Uh, yeah.
差不多吧
Kind of.
猜到了
Figures.
别生气
No offense.
需要帮忙吗
Need any help?
不了  谢谢
No, I'm all right, thanks.
你怎么看这个
What do you think about this?
看上去是朋友嘛
Looks like a friend, no?
从书和装饰来看
Judging by the books and the mascot,
应该是个哲学教授
philosophy professor,
哥谭大学
Gotham U.
值得一试
Worth a shot.
阿门
Amen.
我正要去赴约呢
I was just on my way to an appointment,
是的  我认识斯坦・波托斯基
but yes, I know Stan Potolsky.
他是我的学生
He was a student of mine.
十分聪明
A very brilliant student.
你们这些年一直保持联系
And you've stayed in touch over the years.
是的
We have.
他虽然是生物化学家
He may be a biochemist,
但哲学是他的爱好
but philosophy is a passion of his.
你能跟我们说说韦赞制药解雇他的事吗
What can you tell us about WellZyn firing him?
为韦赞制药做的研究
Research for WellZyn
让他进入了阴暗的道德角落
led him into some dark moral corners.
韦赞说他是做洗发水的
WellZyn said he made shampoo.
这有什么好阴暗道德角落的
Where are the dark moral corners in that?
洗发水
Shampoo?
他们是这么说的
They say that, do they?
不不  斯坦设计
No, no, Stan designed
药物武器
pharmaceutical weapons
给作战部队使用
to be used by combat troops.
这种药对人产生后生作用
Drugs that worked on an epigenetic level.
想象下  一支军队  其士兵无比强壮
Imagine an army made up of soldiers so strong
他们可以用双手将人撕碎
that they can tear a man apart with their bare hands.
当然  起初  药是有副作用的
Of course, at the beginning, there were side effects.
是啊  死亡
Yeah, death.
但毒蛇只是首批药物
But Viper was the first batch.
第二版中他们做了改良
They worked out the kinks in the second version.
并称之为毒液
Called it Venom.
到那时  斯坦有些想通了
By then, Stan had acquired some clarity.
他向上司请求中止这一项目
He appealed to his bosses to end the program.
他们拒绝了  于是他便越级上报
They refused, so he went over their heads
直接找了托马斯和玛莎・韦恩
to Thomas and Martha Wayne.
他说服了他们中止项目
He convinced them to shut it down.
他们死后
And when they died,
韦赞立刻重启了项目
WellZyn immediately revived the program
这次韦恩集团不再干涉
with the blessings of Wayne Enterprises.
最终  斯坦别无选择
In the end, there was nothing for Stan to do
只能采取激进的手段
but to resort to more radical measures.
杀人
Killing people.
你对此似乎并不感到愤怒  教授
I'm not hearing a sense of moral outrage, Professor.
如果你不介意
If you don't mind,
我的愤怒要留给
I'll reserve my moral outrage
这件事中真正的恶人
for the true villains of this piece.
你是指韦赞制药
You mean WellZyn.
是你跟波托斯基合谋
You planned this with Potolsky.
-是的  -他在哪
- Yes. - Where is he?
赶快说
Talk fast, bub!
你能把我怎么样  我一把老骨头  行将就木了
Oh, what are you gonna do to me? I'm an old man! I'm dying.
我希望你早日就木  你个恐怖分子
I'll help you die quicker, you terrorist.
很快  斯通将发表一则声明
Soon, Stan will issue a statement
而世界将无法无视他
the world won't be able to ignore.
很快
Soon?
-今天吗  -你们已经太迟了
- Today? - You're already too late.
-你跟我说他...  -等等
- Now, you tell us where he is right now... - Wait a minute!
等等  你说你要赴约
Wait a minute! You said you had an appointment, right?
你要去哪
Where were you going?
棒极了
Bravo!
你问对问题了
You've asked the right question.
迈出了启蒙的第一步
The first step to enlightenment.
他在哪
Where is he?!
-波托斯基在哪  -那些伪君子
- Where's Potolsky?! - Those hypocrites.
空洞的利他主义无法抹去他们的罪行
Empty altruism will not erase what they've done.
他们必须付出代价
They must pay.
谁  谁要付出代价
Who? Who must pay?
韦赞制药
WellZyn.
韦恩集团
Wayne Enterprises.
大家终将
Everyone will finally
-看清他们的真面目  -怎么看清
- see them for what they are. - How?
波托斯基去哪了
Where's Potolsky headed?
什么是利他主义
What's altruism?!
慈善
Charity.
我知道他去哪了
I know where he's going.
请问您姓名
Name, please?
这是布鲁斯・韦恩
He's, uh, Bruce Wayne.
He's Bruce Wayne.
-这边请  谢谢  -谢谢
- Just this way. Thank you. - Thank you.
韦恩集团
Wayne Enterprises is
是援助之手
a helping hand...
那是玛希斯女士
Oh, that's Miss Mathis.
她跟你父亲有密切合作
She worked closely with your father.
请坐吧  布鲁斯
Please, sit, Bruce.
能见到你出来活动真是太好了
It is so good to see you out and about.
能来我很高兴
Glad to be here.
我们韦恩集团的全体员工都十分替你难过
All of us at Wayne Enterprises are so sorry for your loss.
你们都是董事会成员吗
So, are all you here on the board?
不是的
Oh, heavens no.
我们只是中层管理人员
We're middle management.
董事会不会来参加这种活动
The board members don't do this sort of thing.
是吗
No?
为什么
Why not?
因为他们很忙啊  布鲁斯
Well, they're very busy people, Bruce.
你的家族建立了一个
Your family created a company
价值亿万的公司
worth billions and billions of dollars.
多厉害啊
How awesome is that?
真厉害
Awesome.
我想跟董事会谈谈  因为
I wanted to speak to them because I've found
我在阿卡姆项目中似乎发现了违法行为
what looks like serious irregularities in the Arkham project.
违法行为
Irregularities?
我向你保证  布鲁斯  韦恩集团
I can assure you, Bruce, that Wayne Enterprises
绝不会与罪犯合作
would never countenance doing business with criminals.
-这是不可能的  -希望如此
- Just wouldn't happen. - I hope so,
但我想亲自跟董事会谈谈
but I'd like to speak directly with the board myself.
你能帮我安排吗
Can you make that happen?
我当然会试试
I can certainly try.
发送
他们更喜欢通过法律调解手段
They prefer to communicate with minors
跟未成年人打交道...
via the usual legal mediation, but...
晚上好  女士们先生们
Good evening, ladies and gentleman.
这是代表所有生灵的一则公益宣言
This is a public service announcement on behalf of all living creatures.
你们听说过一种叫毒蛇的药物吗
You've heard of a drug called Viper?
那是我做的
That's me.
是我为韦赞制药做的
I made it for WellZyn,
韦恩集团的一家子公司
a subsidiary of Wayne Enterprises.
是真的吗
Is this true?
当然不是  布鲁斯
Of course not, Bruce.
这人显然是疯了
I mean, this man is clearly insane.
空调机在哪  屋顶吗
The AC plant-- where is it? On the roof?
正前方  舞厅那边的楼梯
Straight ahead, staircase across the ballroom.
清空舞厅
Clear the ballroom!
我本希望用街头游民做演示就足矣
I hoped that a demonstration using street people would suffice,
但看来只有重要人士
but seems bad things only truly happen
遭遇不幸才能引起关注
when they happen to important people.
比如你们
Like you!
哥谭市警局  大家都出去
GCPD! Everybody out!
快走
Now!
关掉
Turn it off!
不行
Can't do that.
关掉  否则我开枪了
Turn it off or I'll shoot!
开枪吧
Go ahead.
我的工作完成了
My work is done.
转过身  把手放在头后
Turn around! Put your hands behind your head!
十指交叉
Interlock your fingers!
没事的
That's all right.
你生气又困惑
You're angry and confused.
这我理解
I understand.
再不需要动用暴力了
There's no more need for violence.
别开枪
Don't shoot!
多谢你了
That's considerate of you.
我要走了
I'm leaving now.
去39号仓库看看
Go look in warehouse 39.
你哪都别想去
You're not going anywhere!
我去哪都行
I can go anywhere I want!
别
Don't do it!
看来好东西也会嫌多
You really can have too much of a good thing.
空的
Nothing.
你以为呢
What'd you expect?
这儿可是哥谭
It's Gotham.
我是玛希斯
It's Mathis.
我在大楼外  他们来了
I'm outside the site. They're here.
不  还是别动他们
No. I think we should leave them be.
他们在这儿什么都找不到
There's nothing here for them.
如果他们查到什么  我们再做考虑
We'll review that if they get close.
韦赞制药  备忘录
都10分钟了
It's been ten minutes.
我保证  我的朋友很可靠
I-I assure you, my friend is reliable.
你怕吗  企鹅
You scared, Penguin?
你的声音又发抖了
Your voice is doing that shaky thing.
没有  先生
No, sir.
我很好
I'm fine.
你不用强撑的
You don't have to act tough.
紧张是好事
Nerves are a good thing.
或许我是有点紧张  先生
Perhaps I am a bit jittery, sir.
很好
Good.
你该紧张
You should be.
如果我的手下出不来  你也别想活
'Cause if my boys don't make it, neither do you.
吃瘪吧  法尔科内  你个孙子
Take that, Falcone, you son of a bitch!
我说了  弗兰基
Huh? I told you, Frankie,
这小子有两下
the kid's a player.
他有前途
He's got a future.
你像个老太太似的磨蹭什么呢  走啊
What are you waiting here like an old lady? Go!
给我解开
Untie me.
说"求你"
Say "pretty please."
求你
Please.
有时候我觉得你不喜欢我
Sometimes I think you really don't like me.
如果我不喜欢你  怎么会支持你接手
Now, would I be backing your takeover if I didn't like you?
在法尔科内面前嘛
And that stuff with Falcone--
总得装装样子给那老头看
well, we have to look good for the old man.
如果他发现我们在合作
If he figures we're working together,
我们就死定了
we'd be cooked.
耐心点
Patience.
我耐心快没了
I have no more patience.
那老头必须死
The old man has to go.
我们得尽快出手
We must strike soon.
是啊
Yes. Mm.
但要温柔一击
But softly.
打扰
Excuse me.
我听到了你哼的那首咏叹调
I couldn't help but overhear that aria you were humming.
是啊  我最喜欢那首了
Oh, yes. It's my favorite.
我也是
Mine, too.
那好啊
Ah, well, there you go.
抱歉
I'm sorry, I-I just...
我没想打扰你的
I-I didn't mean to bother you.
我年轻时  我妈妈总给我唱这首曲子
My mother sang that to me when I was young.
她这辈子  一直给我唱这首歌
Her whole life, she sang that to me.
我好久没听过了
I hadn't heard it in a while, and I...
都忍不住笑出来  你看上去...
I had to smile because you look...
抱歉  我在瞎唠叨呢
Anyhow, sorry, I'm rambling on.
没事的
No, that's okay.
你想听听吗
Do you want to listen?
是啊  好啊  谢谢
Well, yeah. S-Sure, thank you.
我们坐下吧
Let's sit down.
如需其它字幕  请登陆新浪微博[WEB&BD版美剧字幕精编者]
或发邮件 lj20090303@163.com